Suzuno Ota

4-14-3-602 Minami-Azabu, Minato-ku, Tokyo 106-0047 Japan Mobile: +81 (0)90 8453 7117 E-mail: suzuno.ota@gmail.com

OBJECTIVES

To obtain a position of media planner in a global advertising firm.

SUMMARY

Extensive experience in business development & B2B / B2C marketing, PR & communications, event planning and coordination, and CRM management, and paralegal work for over 6 years along with paralegal and secretarial skills. Full-spectrum of multi-faceted work experience and skill sets in multinational work environment for over 14 years.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- · Experience in B2B / B2C marketing, PR and communications, business development
- · Extensive experience in corporate seminar and event planning and coordination
- · Project management skills for launching business as well as product development
- · Extensive English skills with bilingual work office experience for over 14 years
- · Comprehensive back-middle office support experience with multi-tasking and quick mindset
- · Creative skills and background, PC/IT literacy

WORK EXPERIENCE

CLIFFORD CHANCE LAW OFFICE – Tokyo, Japan

04/2013 - Current

Business Development & Marketing Coordinator, Tokyo

- · To support all aspects of the Tokyo office's business development, marketing and client service initiatives by providing proactive support to local and global partners, associates and secretaries
- · To manage and deliver all logistical aspects around marketing and other client events including sourcing venues, creating guest lists, production of invitations, managing logistics during the event, post-event analysis and follow up with clients
- · To maintain an events schedule and inform upcoming events
- · To keep records of client training events, seminars, presentations and general client meetings in order to draw up tailored client reports
- · To update and maintain the Tokyo client lists in the firm's contact management system
- · To work with secretaries to ensure marketing lists are kept up to date
- · To collate and track of proposals and business development activities
- · To maintain and update the internet and internal intranet sites for the Tokyo office
- · To circulate news and market developments to the relevant fee earners, produce periodic newsletters, run financial analysis for key clients
- · To conduct market research, provide client, market and specific sector research/intelligence upon request with the view to identifying business opportunities
- · To produce professional high quality pitches and proposals in English and/or Japanese
- · To manage and update standard BD and marketing materials (capability statements, brochures, deal lists, awards and rankings)

- · To maintain and periodically update partner and associate CVs and profiles
- · To undertake research for pitches and Requests For Proposals via firm-wide resources, online databases and other internal systems
- · To maintain and update internal databases used for capturing deal information and playing a role in key league table submissions
- To create and submit legal directory documents and league tables, including drafting legal award entry submissions and managing the collection of regional rankings and firm accolades
- To handle both internal and external enquiries including from other members of the firm, clients, potential clients, media and suppliers

BAKER & MCKENZIE GAIKOKUHO JOINT ENTERPRISE – Tokyo, Japan 04/2013 – 09/2013

Business Development & Marketing Coordinator, Tokyo

- Plan, execute and assist with various wide range of business development and B2B marketing activities for the lawyers, primarily for Banking & Finance, Capital Markets, Corporate/M&A, Intellectual Property, Real Estate, Environment practice groups in Tokyo and APAC offices.
- Coordinate client seminars, firm-oriented and joint conferences, receptions, and other hospitality projects;
 liaise and coordinate with all stakeholders including clients and lawyers, venders, external event organizers,
 internal design and operation teams; handle pre and post-event logistics including budgeting and data
 management.
- · Draft proposals, research potential clients, prepare pitch, capability and RFP documents in both English and Japanese by liaising with lawyers and other professionals (primarily responsible for Japanese documents, which were recognized for the highest win rate in the team).
- · Originate, review, edit, translate and update marketing materials including lawyers' biographies, brochures, presentations and articles for publication in both English and Japanese.
- · Attend Partners business development and practice group meetings and prepare meeting minutes.
- Manage CRM lists and client database; analyze and create mailing lists of targeted clients via CRM database; initiate internet/web marketing plans and distribute e-mail campaigns via CRM system and other media.
- · Collect and update client information in CRM; research on potential clients and execute analysis; prepare proposal documents by liaising with lawyers to accelerate pipelines and projects.
- · Perform research on key / target clients, share news clippings with the entire office, identify legal industry news and share the same.
- · Handle PR and Communications tasks and liaise with publishers; coordinate tie-up and sponsorship events, prepare and distribute press release documents specific to assigned practice areas, distribute press releases.
- · Upload and update marketing related information, biographies, and publications on website.
- · Handle deal/matter collection and information management; input and track business development activities e.g. published articles, credentials and pitch activity feedback in the firm's tracker system.
- · Prepare legal directory, award, and nomination submissions for third party publications and organizations.
- · Handle ad-hoc requests e.g. event related logistics and administrative works, travel arrangements, budgeting, etc.

HOGAN LOVELLS HORITSU JIMUSHO GAIKOKUHO KYODO JIGYO – Tokyo, Japan 04/2012 – 03/2013

Business Development Coordinator, Tokyo

- · Handle the overall business development, marketing and PR activities for the Tokyo office as the single coordinator.
- · Coordinate regional and office events and handle the entire pre and post-event management including panel and speaking engagements, substantive seminars and conferences, social events and receptions; handling wide range of logistical event preparation and execution works; liaise with wide range of external and

internal stakeholders involved.

- Plan campaign themes with lawyers, promote the event via campaigns, create mailing / invitees list generated from CRM system, create and send out e-campaign / invitation, RSVP management, material preparation, registration and distribution list maintenance, venue and vendor communication, etc. (Achieved the highest RSVP counts amongst the seminars hosted by the Asia Pacific offices at one of the seminars, CLE-accredited US patent seminars, organized by myself.)
- · Assist with collateral data management and production in Japanese and English, i.e. a full suite of marketing collaterals, including office and practice profiles, lawyers' profiles, and PowerPoint and Word presentations.
- · Manage to create and print bilingual business brochures, proposals, credentials statements, proposals and seminar materials.
- Collaborate with the Regional Business Development Team and local partners to coordinate public relations opportunities and handle external communications, including article placement and coordinating media interviews.
- · Manage and update collateral documents and CRM systems ensuring that key information systems such as the credentials, case / experience and CV database as well as marketing lists and contact information in CRM systems are kept up-to-date (InterAction, FileMaker, etc.).
- · Coordinate legal directory submissions, awards submissions and other surveys.
- · Manage regular updates of web pages for global site; feature recent awards, topics and event information; coordinate with headquarter web and practice managers for website improvement.
- · Assist with special ad-hoc projects as required including client, industry and market research.
- · Support visiting partners with general administrative matters for their business development visits to Japan.

ROPES & GRAY, LLP - Tokyo, Japan

08/2008 - 03/2012

Legal Secretary, Intellectual Property, Litigation Practice

- · Assist creating and updating firm brochures, marketing collaterals, office and practice profiles, biographies, and presentations; arrange print delivery.
- · Liaise with attorneys and internal and external contacts to plan logistics and coordinate external marketing events e.g. joint seminars with local law firms; handle pre and post seminar logistics.
- · Coordinate and manage teleconference and live seminars, lectures, social events and receptions based on budget and objectives; communicate with venues, caterers, interpreters, AV and other venders, inter-office and joint-hosts as an intermediary.
- · Create and keep office and firm mailing and invitation lists up-to-date in CRM (InterAction) database; assist with building CRM database in the office to utilize for various marketing events, webinars and teleseminars; update contact information; coordinate with US marketing team to send out invitations and other announcements; monitor RSVPs and create reports.
- Trained teammates on CRM and other firm applications. Assigned local lawyers were ranked up to Tier 2 in IP international ranking from not-ranked position in Chambers and Partners Asia Pacific during my employment.
- · Assist multiple partners and associates encompassing broad-ranged legal secretarial and administrative support, contributing Tokyo and IP litigation partners since the early stage of office establishment in Japan.
- Handle on-demand secretarial and administrative tasks: scheduling, liaising with external contacts, transcribing, formatting and modifying documentation per guidance, creating firm brochures and marketing materials, client and vendor billing and expensing, inputting time entries, filing, processing conflict checking, assisting with bar registration and visa matters, etc.
- · Provide administrative support for visiting attorneys and guest speakers; assist attorneys with post-seminar reports, e.g. cost summary and attendance report.

Technical Translator / Product Quality Inspector / Group Assistant, Specialty Materials Division

- Function as an exclusive technical translator and primary liaison between American engineers and external parties, contributing to the development and reinforcement of interrelationship between the parties involved.
- · Provide simultaneous interpretation in meetings; translate R&D documents; searched relevant arts.
- · Utilize inspection ability to detect 2-3 µm level defects to produce samples (critical aspect in developing process line and quality baseline for the entire project) as quality inspector and candidate for application engineer.

SAKAI & ASSOCIATES - Nagano, Japan

02/2004 - 09/2005

Paralegal, International Intellectual Property Prosecution

- · Coordinate translators' schedule; proofread translation of specification documents; research prior-arts.
- · Translate Office Actions from designated countries patent offices, assist with preparing OA responses.
- · Provide legal, administrative assistance to president and patent engineers.
- · Liaise with local representatives and law firms to file and manage filings of patent, design, etc. to prosecute intellectual property rights in designated countries as the sole bilingual paralegal in the office.
- · Monitor deadlines; prepare prosecution documents for filing, and maintenance documents; manage and docket case files.
- Translate correspondence for the office managing patent attorney; communicate with law firms and vendors.
- · Handle translation cost and expense processing, POs, couriers, etc.

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RF SYSTEM LAB. CO., LTD. - Nagano, Japan

08/2002 - 12/2003

Lead Translator / Sales Representative, Overseas Sales Department

- · Translate product brochures, instruction manuals, and specifications; designed the same with DTP team.
- · Expedite marketing and sales of intraoral and dermatological devices to overseas medical practitioners.
- · B2C telephone marketing of intraoral equipment to dentists in Australia, New Zealand, and U.S.A.

THE HYAKUGO BANK, LTD. – New York, NY, U.S.A.

06/2001 - 06/2002

Intern Administrative Assistant / Researcher, New York Representative Office (OPT Practical Training / Internship)

- · Perform research of new financial products and trend in financial and banking industries in America; translate research documents to report to Headquarters; assist with drafting reports; translate articles from finance / banking related magazines and newspapers.
- · Provide office administrative and secretarial support for chief resident expatriate and senior expatriates.
- · Handle reception works and communicate with local contacts and vendors on behalf.
- · Assist with coordinating Mie-Kenjin-Kai annual party.

KAIKAI KIKI CO., LTD. – New York, NY, U.S.A.

06/2001 - 07/2002

Part-time Studio Assistant to *Takashi Murakami*, Hiropon Factory New York Brooklyn Studio (OPT Practical Training)

- · Liaise with local galleries and museums for exhibitions and promotion of art works.
- · Provide assistance to create Takashi Murakami's large-size paintings and sculpture art works.

- · Install art works at various landmarks in New York City for exhibitions.
- · Handle miscellaneous studio management related tasks.

FUNIMATION PRODUCTIONS, LTD. – Dallas/Fort Worth, TX, U.S.A.

11/1999 - 06/2000

Part-time Japanese Animation Translator

- · Translate and create draft scripts of Japanese animation episodes and these songs for broadcast and DVD production in U.S.A., e.g. *Dragon Ball, Dragon Ball Z, Yuyu Hakusho*, etc.
- · Attend to voice recording and sensor prohibited terminologies for broadcasting and DVD productions.

EDUCATION

Texas Christian University – Fort Worth, TX, U.S.A. 12/2000

B.F.A., Bachelor's Degree in Fine Arts, Painting

Sculpture Studio & Gallery Assistant for the Faculty of Fine Arts Department 01/1999 – 05/2001

HONORS & ACHIEVEMENTS

1998-1999 Nordan Scholarship

1999-2000 Emily Guthrie Smith Scholarship

FOREIGN LANGUAGE SKILLS

English: TOEIC: 975 (2005), TOEFL: 630 (2001)

COMPUTER SKILLS

- · Microsoft Outlook, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Adobe Suite, Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Just System, Quark Express, Paint Shop Pro, WebView, Elite, and other legal applications (InterAction, FileMaker Pro, Legal Keys, Delta View, etc.)
- · Certificate of Microsoft PowerPoint Expert, March 2012
- · Hatarako-Net 12th PC Skill Test, MS Word & Typing National Deviation 80, Rating: 1/1,205
- · Typing Speed: approx. 95 wpm, 10-key experience

REFERENCES

Available upon request.